A Guide to the Lester M. Salamon Papers FA1868
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Writings, 1969-2022; 1; 27.62 Cubic Feet (72 containers)
  - Partners in Public Service Toward a Theory of Government-Nonprofit Relations, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 197)
  - Nonprofits and the New Federal Budget, undated (Box 23, Folder 198)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 199-200)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Front Matter, undated (Box 23, Folder 201)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 1, undated (Box 23, Folder 202)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 2, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 203)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 3, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 204)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 4, undated (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 5, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 206)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Chapter 6, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 207)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the New Federal Budget - Appendices, undated (Box 24, Folder 208)
  - Government and the Voluntary Sector in an Era of Retrenchment: The American Experience, 1986-1987 (Box 24, Folder 209)
  - Partners in Public Service: Perspectives on Government-Nonprofit Relations, 1986-1992 (Box 24, Folder 210)
  - The Federal Government and the Nonprofit Sector: The Impact of the 1981 Tax Act of Individual Charitable Gviing, 1981-1984 (Box 25, Folder 211)
  - New Tax Law Is Said to Endanger Billions in Gifts to Private Groups, New York Times, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 212)
  - Marin Testimony, Buck Trust Trial, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 213)
  - Managers and Donors: The Buck Trust Case, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 214)
  - Lester M. Salamon Testimony, Buck Trust Trial, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 215)
  - Changing Public/Private Roles in Human Services, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 216)
  - The Changing Technology of Public Action: An Introduction, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 217)
  - The Nonprofit Sector: International and Comparative Perspectives, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 218)
  - The Rise of Third-Party Government and the Decline of the American State, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 220)
  - Giving a Wealth of Goodwill, Insight, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 221)
  - Rise of Third-Party Government, 1986-1990 (Box 26, Folder 222)
  - Economic Development, Baltimore Sun, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 223)
  - Chicago Model Drafts, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 224)
  - Of Market Failure, Voluntary Failure, and Third-Party Government: Toward a Theory of Government-Nonprofit Relations in the Modern Welfare State, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 225-226)
  - Governance: The Politics of Retrenchment, Reagan Record, 1988-1994 (Box 26, Folder 227)
  - Nonprofit Organizations: The Lost Opportunity, Reagan Record, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 228)
  - The Reagan Administration and the Nonprofit Sector: The Lost Opportunity, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 229)
  - The Reagan Economic Recovery Program and Community-Based Organizations, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 230)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and the Rise of Third-Party Government: The Scope, Character, and Consequences of Government Support of Nonprofit Organizations, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 231-232)
  - Nonprofits and the Poor Survey Results, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 233)
  - The New Federalism, the Federal Budget, and the Nonprofit Sector, Testimony before the Joint Economic Committee, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 234)
  - Families in Crisis: The Capacity of Private Nonprofit Agencies to Respond, Testimony before the Select Committee on Children, Youth, and Families, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 235)
  - Voluntary Organizations and the Crisis of the Welfare State, 1983-1987 (Box 28, Folder 236-238)
  - The Federal Budget and the Nonprofit Sector, Abramson, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 239-243)
  - Me and My Tax Cut, The Washington Post, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 244)
  - The Reagan Economic Recovery Program and the Nonprofit Sector: An Overview and Update, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 245)
  - The Economic Recovery Program and the Nonprofit Sector: Overview and Update, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 246)
  - The Voluntary Sector and the Future of the Welfare State - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 247)
  - Who Benefits? The Nonprofit Sector and the Distribution of Income in the United States, 1990-1991 (Box 30, Folder 248-249)
  - The Charitable Behavior of the Charitable Sector: The Case of Social Services, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 250-252)
    Prepared for "Who Benefits? The Distributional Consequences of the Nonprofit Sector" by Charles Clotfelter.
  - Government and the Third Sector, B. Gidron, R. Kramer, L. Salamon (The Israel Conference Book), 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 253-255)
  - The Interrelationship between the Public and Voluntary Sector in Switzerland, Wagner (Isreal Conference Book), 1989-1991 (Box 32, Folder 256)
  - Moving towards the Market, Marylin Taylor (Isreal Conference Book), 1991 (Box 32, Folder 257)
  - Government and the Nonprofit Sector in Comparative Perspective - Overview, B. Gidron, R. Kramer, L. Salamon, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 258)
  - The Stakes in Regulatory Reform: A Political Analysis, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 259)
  - Local Development Reorganization Project - Organizing for Development Final Report, Reorganization Study of Federal Community and Economic Development Programs, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 260)
  - The Budget: A Weak Reed, The Wall Street Journal, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 261)
  - The Rise of Third-Party Government, Washington Post, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 262-263)
  - Welfare Reform: Back to Basics, 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 264)
  - In Pursuit of Reorganization: The Question of Goals, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 265-266)
  - The Illusion of Presidential Government, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 267-268)
  - Mississippi as a "Developing Society": The Political Economy of Southern Poverty and Change, undated (Box 34, Folder 269-272)
  - Tools of Philanthropy Project, Urban Institute, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 342)
  - Bankamerica Foundation Establishes Neighborhood Partnership Loan Fund for Community Development, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 343)
  - Piton Foundation - Federal Taxation and Charitable Giving to Nonprofit Organizations, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 344)
  - Economic Structural Change - Work and Change: Labor Market Adjustment Policies in a Competitive World, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 345)
  - New Tools of Public Action (Aetna) - General, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 346-347)
  - New Tools of Public Action (Aetna) - Draft Proposal, undated (Box 42, Folder 348)
  - New Tools of Public Action (Aetna) - Resources, 1980-1985 (Box 42, Folder 349)
  - Forms of Government Action Addendum - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 42, Folder 350)
  - Forms of Government Action Addendum - General, 1981-1983 (Box 42, Folder 351)
  - Forms of Government Action Addendum - Third-Party Government and the Transformation of the Public Sector Draft, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 352)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (NAPA) Privatization Articles, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 360-361)
  - Public Analysis Framework, Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1981-1986 (Box 43, Folder 362)
  - Federal Regulation: A New Arena for Presidential Power?, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 363)
  - Federal Regulation: A New Arena for Presidential Power? - Talking Points, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 364)
  - Federal Regulation: A New Arena for Presidential Power? - Draft, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 365)
  - Federal Regulation: A New Arena for Presidential Power? - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 366)
  - Emergency Land Fund, President's Reorganization Project, 1977-1979 (Box 44, Folder 367)
  - The Resilient Sector: The State of Nonprofit America, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 791-792)
  - State of Nonprofit America, 2nd Edition - Notes, 2008-2012 (Box 90, Folder 878-879)
  - Various Salamon Articles, 1982-1993 (Box 98, Folder 928-929)
  - The Nonprofit Sector and Democracy: Prerequisite, Impediment, or Irrelevance?, 2002 (Box 101, Folder 951)
  - The Civil Society Sector, 1997 (Box 101, Folder 952)
  - Toward an Understanding of the International Nonprofit Sector: The Johns Hopkins Comparative Nonprofit Sector Project, 1992 (Box 101, Folder 953)
  - The Nonprofit Workforce Crisis - Real or Imagined?, 2009 (Box 101, Folder 954)
  - Managing Foundation Assets: An Analysis of Foundation Investment Procedures and Performance, 1987 (Box 101, Folder 957)
  - Charities Need More Investment Capital, Chronicle of Philanthropy, undated (Box 102, Folder 967)
  - Taxing the Tax-Exempt Sector - A Growing Danger for Nonprofit Organizations, 2011 (Box 102, Folder 968)
  - Explaining Nonprofit Advocacy: An Exploratory Analysis, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 1123)
  - The Real Meaning on September 11 for Nonprofit America, 2002 (Box 111, Folder 1124)
  - The Nonprofit Sector at a Crossroads: The Case of America, Voluntas, 1999 (Box 111, Folder 1125)
  - Compassionate Conservatism Takes A Bow, The Economist, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 1126)
  - The Changing Context of of Nonprofit Leadership and Management, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 1127)
  - The New Governance and the Tools of Public Action: An Introduction, Fordham Urban Law Journal, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 1128)
  - The Changing Social Compact for Nonprofits, Independent Sector Civic Engagement Task Force, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 1129)
  - The Voluntary Sector and the Future of the Welfare State, undated (Box 111, Folder 1130)
  - Market Considerations for Nonprofits, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 1131)
  - Enron and Charities, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 1132)
  - The Broader Lessons of September 11, 2002 (Box 111, Folder 1133)
  - The U.S. Nonprofit Sector: Scope, Structure, and Trends, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 1134)
  - Civic Life and Economic Growth, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 1135)
  - Explaining Nonprofit Advocacy: An Exploratory Analysis, 2002 (Box 111, Folder 1137)
  - Nonprofits and Stimulus, 2007-2008 (Box 111, Folder 1138)
  - A Policy Agenda to Support the Financial Security of the Social Sector, Greenblatt, 2012 (Box 111, Folder 1141)
  - Nonprofits to the Rescue, Chronicles of Philanthropy, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 1142)
  - Nonprofit America: An Overview, National Academy of Sciences, 2014 (Box 112, Folder 1146)
  - Warrant Our Future Op-Ed, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 1153)
  - Pocantico Declaration, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 1154)
  - Where Has All the Giving Gone?, 2009 (Box 112, Folder 1155)
  - Volunteering in Cross-National Perspective, Law and Contemporary Problems, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 1280)
  - The Nonprofit Sector: For What and For Whom?, ISTR Paper, 2000 (Box 121, Folder 1286)
  - Toward an Enabling Legal Environment for Civil Society, 2001-2007 (Box 121, Folder 1290)
  - Third Sector, Philanthropy, and Social Economy: Concepts, Myths, and Trends, undated (Box 122, Folder 1296)
  - The Nonprofit Sector in Comparative Perspective, 2003 (Box 122, Folder 1302)
  - Social Origins of the Nonprofit Sector: A Cross-National Comparision, 2000 (Box 122, Folder 1309)
  - Social Origins of Civil Society: Explaining the Nonprofit Sector Cross-Nationally, Voluntas, 1998 (Box 122, Folder 1310)
  - The Prospects for Civil Society - Mexico and the World, CEMFEI, 2005 (Box 125, Folder 1348)
  - Putting Nonprofit Institutions on the Economic Map of the World, SNA Article, undated (Box 125, Folder 1349)
  - Philanthropy's Blind Spot, Alliance Volunteer Article, undated (Box 126, Folder 1370)
  - Economic Value of Volunteer Work, Annals of Public and Cooperative Economics, 2011 (Box 127, Folder 1372)
  - Civil Society and Power: Toward A Social Origins Explanation of Civil Society Development, 2012 (Box 127, Folder 1376)
  - The Influence of the Legal Environment on the Development of the Nonprofit Sector, 2000 (Box 127, Folder 1378)
  - Devolution, Privatization, and the Changing Shape of Government-Nonprofit Relations - Draft, undated (Box 133, Folder 1468)
  - Handbook of Research on Economics and Management - Foreward, undated (Box 133, Folder 1474)
  - The Marketization of Welfare: Changing Nonprofit and For-Profit Roles in the American Welfare State, 1993 (Box 133, Folder 1475)
  - Impact of the 2008-09 Economic Recession on Nonprofit Organizations, 2009 (Box 138, Folder 1548)
  - The Presidency and National Policy I - Changing Context: Interdependence, Third Party Government, and the New Pluralism, 1980 (Box 138, Folder 1529)
  - Poem - To the Peanut, undated (Box 139, Folder 1533)
  - Poem - The Ballad of Anita the Mac, undated (Box 139, Folder 1534)
  - Financial Needs Can Hinder Charities from Helping the Needy, Says Scholar, The Chronicle of Philnathropy, 2012 (Box 139, Folder 1536)
  - Foreword Together: Empowering America's Citizen Sector for the Change We Need, Johns Hopkins University Project, undated (Box 139, Folder 1537)
  - Holiday Letter, Johns Hopkins University, 2012 (Box 139, Folder 1539)
  - The Stakes in the Rural South - Family Assistance, 1971 (Box 139, Folder 1542)
  - The Buck Starts Here, New York Times, 1976 (Box 139, Folder 1543)
  - Leadership and Modernization: The Emerging Black Political Elite in the American South, Journal of Politics, 1977 (Box 139, Folder 1544)
  - Federalism in 1971: The Crisis Continues, 1972 (Box 139, Folder 1545)
- Speeches and Presentations, 1996-2021; 2; 7.98 Cubic Feet (21 containers)
  This series contains copies of Powerpoints, slide decks, notes, and speeches.
  - The New Governance: Getting Beyond the Right Answer to the Wrong Question in Public Sector Reform, J. Douglas Gibson Lecture, undated (Box 58, Folder 512)
  - Resolved: That Third-Party Government Diminishes Public Accountability, NAPA Fall Meeting Debate Opening Remarks, 2007 (Box 58, Folder 514)
  - Training Professional Citizens: Getting Beyond the Right Answer to the Wrong Question in Public Affairs Education, Johns Hopkins University Keynote Address, 2004 (Box 58, Folder 515)
  - The New Governance and Tools of Public Action: Implications for Canada's Voluntary Sector Initiative, 2005 (Box 58, Folder 516)
  - Why Partner?, Partnering for Results Insititute, 2004 (Box 58, Folder 517)
  - Comments on "Managing Federal Missions with a Miltisector Workforce", NAPA Panel Meeting, 2005 (Box 58, Folder 518)
  - Italy's Charitable Alchemy, ACRI 20th Anniversary Speech, 2010 (Box 68, Folder 688)
  - The State of Nonprofit America - CNP Phase II and IIB Presentation, undated (Box 76, Folder 793)
  - SOS II and Values Speech, 2012-2018 (Box 103, Folder 974)
  - Volunteer Measurement Project, IAVE Conference, Panama, 2008 (Box 103, Folder 975)
  - Philanthropication thru Privatization: Building Permanent Assets for Social Progress, Denmark, 2020 (Box 103, Folder 976)
  - Unbriefing, UN Presentation, OTL, 2020 (Box 103, Folder 977)
  - 10 Great Myths of Civil Society, China Global Philanthropy Institute (CGPI), 2017 (Box 103, Folder 978)
  - Global Civil Society, New Zealand, 2008 (Box 103, Folder 979)
  - COVID-19 and the Nonprofit Workforce: U.S. and Georgia, 2020 (Box 103, Folder 980)
  - Putting NPIs and the Third Sector on the Economic Map of Europe, Eurostat, 2016 (Box 103, Folder 981)
  - Putting the TSE Sector on the Economic Map of the World: The Statistical Revolution, Ukraine UNTSE Workshop, 2018 (Box 103, Folder 982)
  - The New Governance and the Nonprofitization of the Welfare State, I-Lab Conference, 2015 (Box 103, Folder 983)
  - 10 Myths of Global Civil Society, Kyrgyz National University, 2013 (Box 103, Folder 984)
  - Measuring the Social Economy in Europe: A National Accounts Approach, Luxembourg, 2014 (Box 103, Folder 985)
  - Putting the Third Sector on the Economic Map of the World: A Statistical Revolution, Workshop on Measurement of the Third Sector in China, 2019 (Box 103, Folder 986)
  - 10 Great Myths of Global Civil Society, Uzbekistan, 2017 (Box 103, Folder 987)
  - Foundation Realities and Possibilities: An Overview, China Donor Roundtable, 2017 (Box 103, Folder 988)
  - Putting the Third Sector/Social Economy on the Statistical Map of Europe, TSI Project Final Conference, Brussels, 2016 (Box 103, Folder 989)
  - Chile's Civil Society Sector in Comparative Perspective, 2017 (Box 103, Folder 990)
  - Conceptualizing the Third Sector, NR Higher School of Economics, 2016 (Box 104, Folder 991)
  - Philanthropication thru Privatization: Building Permanent Assets for Social Progress, Anti-Corruption Action Network (ACAN), 2018 (Box 104, Folder 992)
  - Center For Civil Society Studies (CCSS): Overview, undated (Box 104, Folder 993)
  - The Revolution in Social Purpose Finance, 2014 (Box 104, Folder 994)
  - Independent Sector Nonprofit Forum, 2019 (Box 104, Folder 995)
  - The New Governance and the Tools of Public Action, World Bank Presentation, 2019 (Box 104, Folder 996)
  - Philanthropication thru Privatization: Building Permanent Assets for Social Progress, 2017 (Box 104, Folder 997)
  - In Search of Nonprofit Value Proposition, MANO Summit, 2015 March (Box 107, Folder 1075)
  - Arnova Distinguished Achievement Award Acceptance Speech, 2001-2003 (Box 110, Folder 1120)
  - Nonprofit Trends, 2001-2002 (Box 110, Folder 1121)
  - Keeping the Faith Speech, undated (Box 110, Folder 1122)
  - The State of Nonprofit America: Challenges, Opportunities, Response Powerpoint, Weinberg Fellows, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 1136)
  - The State of Nonprofit America, GAO Seminar, 2007 (Box 111, Folder 1140)
  - Gathering of Leaders, Miami, 2009 February (Box 112, Folder 1143)
  - Center for Civil Society Presentation, 2013 (Box 112, Folder 1145)
  - Social Origins of Civil Society: Explaining the Nonprofit Sector Cross-Nationally, 1996 (Box 120, Folder 1266)
  - The Three Faces of the Third Sector, Third Ibero-American Conference on the Third Sector, 1996 (Box 120, Folder 1268)
  - The Third Sector and Volunteering in Global Perspective, 2001 (Box 121, Folder 1284)
  - Partners in Public Service: Government and the Civil Society Sector in the Battle to Alleviate Child Poverty, 2002 (Box 121, Folder 1295)
  - Building Democracy from the Grassroots, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 1301)
  - Civil Society in Global Perspective Powerpoint, 2002 (Box 122, Folder 1304)
  - The Third Sector in Global Perspective, IAF Speech, 2002 (Box 122, Folder 1305)
  - The Global Associational Revolution: Its Implications for Philanthropy, New Zealand Speech, 2003 (Box 122, Folder 1306)
  - The Global Associational Revolution: Why?, Carnegie Seminar Presentation, 2003 (Box 123, Folder 1315)
  - Sociedad Civil Global (Global Civil Society), Chile Presentation, 2006 (Box 123, Folder 1321)
  - Youth Entrepreneurship and Volunteerism Presentation, Peru, 2004 (Box 124, Folder 1323)
  - Global Civil Society II Presentation - Revisions, 2004 (Box 124, Folder 1324)
  - UN Nonprofit Institution Handbook, Brussels Presentation, 2004 (Box 124, Folder 1331)
  - Great Myths of Civil Society, Toronto, 2005-2006 (Box 125, Folder 1344)
  - UN Handbook Briefing Presentation, undated (Box 125, Folder 1345)
  - The Scale of Nonprofit Activity, 39 Countries, CNP Chile Powerpoint, 2006 (Box 125, Folder 1350)
  - UN-NGO Conference Speech, 2006 (Box 126, Folder 1353)
  - Civil Society and Democracy Powerpoint, UNDP, undated (Box 126, Folder 1354)
  - Out of the Shadows: Putting Civil Society on the Economic Map of the World, Eurostat Conference on Developing Statistics, 2008 (Box 126, Folder 1356)
  - The Meaning of Oliver Twist School: Towards A New Model of Public Problem-Solving, Cometa Speech, Italy, 2009 (Box 126, Folder 1357)
  - Putting Volunteerism on the Economic Map of the World, ISTR Presentation, undated (Box 126, Folder 1358)
  - Are We Moving Toward A Three-Sector Society?, Keynote Address, 10th Anniversary Conference of the Israeli Center for Third Sector Research, 2005-2008 (Box 126, Folder 1362)
  - Three Sector Society Speech, Arnova, 2010 (Box 126, Folder 1363)
  - U.S. Lessons for China's Nonprofits Speech Notes, 2011 (Box 126, Folder 1364)
  - Communicating with Government and International Bodies, HPM Research and Practice Retreat Speech, 2011 (Box 126, Folder 1366)
  - European Volunteer Measurement Powerpoint, undated (Box 126, Folder 1367)
  - Putting Volunteering on the Economic Map of the World - A Historic Opportunity, 2008 (Box 126, Folder 1368)
  - Putting Civil Society and Volunteering on the Economic Map of Latin America, IDB Presentation, HB and Manual, 2011 (Box 126, Folder 1369)
  - Global Civil Society- Comparative Nonprofit Sector Project, Turkey Powerpoint, 2012 (Box 127, Folder 1375)
  - Global Civil Society - Index Powerpoint, 2012 (Box 127, Folder 1379)
  - International Work Presentation, World Bank Sessions, 2012 (Box 127, Folder 1385)
  - Mexico Nonprofit Powerpoint, 2012 (Box 127, Folder 1386)
  - Myths of Global Civil Society, University of Virginia, 2010 (Box 128, Folder 1390)
  - Volunteering and Social Capital, Brazil, 2012 (Box 128, Folder 1391)
  - Volunteer Measurement: The Global Challenge, Budapest, 2012 (Box 128, Folder 1395)
  - Putting Volunteer Work on the Economic Map of the World: Why and How?, EESC Session, Warsaw, 2011 (Box 128, Folder 1404)
  - Nonprofit Data, Arnova Presentation, 2015 (Box 129, Folder 1420)
  - Myths of Civil Society - Updated Presentation, 2013 (Box 129, Folder 1424)
  - Luxembourg Handbook Powerpoints, 2019 (Box 132, Folder 1460)
  - Speech Material, 2005 (Box 133, Folder 1471)
  - An Innovative Response to Africa's Debt Crisis, West Africa Debt Advocacy Meeting, 2021 (Box 134, Folder 1493)
  - The Nonprofit Workforce: Why Church Mutual Clients Should Care, Surviving the Cost of COVID, Church Mutual Insurance, 2021 (Box 134, Folder 1494)
- Books, 1964-2020; 3; 8.47 Cubic Feet (10 containers)
  This series contains copies of books written by Lester Salamon as well as books from his personal library.
  - The Reagan Record: An Assessment of American's Changing Domestic Priorities, John L. Palmer and Isabel V. Sawhill, 1984 (Box 46)
  - Nonprofit Management and Leadership, Volume 3, Number 3, 1993 Spring (Box 46)
  - Leverage for Good: An Introduction to the New Frontiers of Philanthropy and Social Investment, Lester M. Salamon, 2014 (Box 46)
  - Leverage for Good: An Introduction to the New Frontiers of Philanthropy and Social Investment, Lester M. Salamon, 2014 (Box 46)
  - Explaining Civil Society Development: A Social Origins Approach, Lester M. Salmon, S. Wojciech Sokolowski, and Megan A. Haddock, 2017 (Box 46)
  - Philanthopication thru Privatization: Building Permanent Endowments for the Common Good, Lester M. Salamon, 2014 (Box 46)
  - Handbook of Research on Nonprofit Economics and Management, Bruce A. Seaman and Dennis R. Young, 2018 (Box 46)
  - The Future of the Industrial City: The Challenge of Economic Change in America and Europe, Lester M. Salamon, 1990 (Box 46)
  - New Frontiers of Philanthropy: A Guide to the New Tools and Actors Reshaping Global Philanthropy and Social Investing, Lester M. Salamon, 2014 (Box 46)
  - The State of Nonprofit America, Lester M. Salamon, 2012 (Box 46)
  - La Sociedad Civil Global: Las Dimensiones del Sector No Lucrativo, Lester M. Salamon, 1999 (Box 46)
  - Partners in Public Service: Government-Nonprofit Relations in the Modern Welfare State, Lester M. Salamon, 1995 (Box 46)
  - The Third Sector As A Renewable Resource for Europe: Concepts, Impacts, Challenges and Opportunities, Bernard Enjorlas, Lester M. Salamon, Karl Henrik Sivesind, and Annette Zimmer, 2018 (Box 46)
  - Beyond Privatization: The Tools of Government Action, Lester M. Salamon, 1989 (Box 46)
  - Global Civil Society: Dimensions of the Nonprofit Sector, Volume 2, 2007 (Box 46)
  - American Intergovernmental Relations Today: Perspectives and Controversies, Robert Jay Dilger, 1986 (Box 47)
  - Terzo Settore, Stato e Mercato Nella Tranformazione delle Politiche Sociali in Europa, Giovanna Rossi, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Voluntas, Volume 10, Number 1, 1999 March (Box 47)
    Contains "The Nonprofit Sector at a Crossroads: The Case of America" by Lester M. Salamon. Two copies.